* * * *

* * * *
    
* * * *
    
* Toggle theme
    * Light
    * Dark
    * Auto

Terms & Privacy
===============

Terms of Use
------------

Open-Meteo assumes no responsibility for any inaccuracies or omissions in the data, their availability, or any losses or damages resulting from their usage. The accuracy and completeness of the data products and their uninterrupted provision are not guaranteed by Open-Meteo, and they are provided without any warranty, either statutory or otherwise. In any event, Open-Meteo disclaims all liability under these Terms of Use, whether arising from contract, tort, or any other cause.

### Non-Commercial Use

By using the Free API for non-commercial use you agree to following terms:

* Less than 10'000 API calls per day, 5'000 per hour and 600 per minute.
* You may only use the free API services for non-commercial purposes.
* You accept to the CC-BY 4.0 license, as specified in the [license conditions](https://open-meteo.com/en/license "Open-Meteo further license details").
* We reserve the right to block applications and IP addresses that misuse our service without prior notice.

Non-commercial use is defined as as [elaborated by creative commons](https://wiki.creativecommons.org/wiki/NonCommercial_interpretation). To make it easier to understand, here are some examples that qualify as non-commercial use:

* Using our service for private or non-profit websites or apps that do not have subscriptions or advertising.
* Utilizing our service for personal home automation purposes.
* Using our service for public research conducted at public institutions.
* Incorporating our service into educational content.

On the other hand, the following examples are considered commercial use:

* Operating websites or apps that have subscriptions or display advertisements.
* Integrating our service into commercial products or promotional activities.
* Conducting undisclosed research at commercial entities.

If you plan to use our service for commercial purposes or require additional API calls, we kindly request you to consider subscribing to our API plans as explained in detail on the [pricing](https://open-meteo.com/en/pricing "Pricing information to use the weather API commercially") page. Your subscription helps support the continuous development, maintenance, and support of Open-Meteo.

### API Subscription

When using the [paid API subscription](https://open-meteo.com/en/pricing "Pricing information to use the weather API commercially"), you agree to the following terms:

* By subscribing to our service, you authorize us to charge the applicable subscription fees through the payment gateway Stripe.
* You agree to provide accurate and up-to-date payment information and promptly update it if there are any changes.

Account and Security:

* You are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality and security of your account login credentials.
* You agree not to share your account or login information with any third party.
* You are solely responsible for any activities that occur under your account.

Intellectual Property:

* All intellectual property rights in our SaaS service, including but not limited to software, content, and trademarks, belong to us.
* You are granted a limited, non-exclusive, and non-transferable license to use our service for the duration of your subscription.
* The data obtained through the API is provided under the terms of the CC-BY 4.0 license, as specified in the [license conditions](https://open-meteo.com/en/license "Open-Meteo further license details").

Limitation of Liability:

* Our service is provided on an "as is" and "as available" basis without any warranties, express or implied.
* We do not guarantee the accuracy, completeness, or reliability of our service or its suitability for your specific needs.
* We shall not be liable for any indirect, incidental, consequential, or punitive damages arising from or related to your use of our service.
* Our total liability, if any, shall be limited to the amount you paid for the subscription fee during the twelve months preceding the claim.

Termination:

* Either party may terminate the subscription at the end of each payment schedule, for any reason, with or without notice.
* Upon missed payments, we reserve the right to terminate the subscription and access to our service after 14 days.
* Upon termination, your access to the service and any associated data may be immediately deactivated.

We reserve the right to modify these terms of use at any time. Any changes will be effective immediately upon posting the revised terms on our website. All changes are transparently tracked on [GitHub](https://github.com/open-meteo/open-meteo-website/commits/main/src/routes/en/terms/%2Bpage.svelte "Modification history of terms of service").

Governing Law: These terms of use shall be governed by and construed in accordance with the laws of Switzerland. Any disputes arising from or in connection with these terms shall be subject to the exclusive jurisdiction of the courts in Switzerland. Please read these terms of use carefully before using our paid API subscription. If you have any questions or concerns, please contact us at [info@open-meteo.com](mailto:info@open-meteo.com).

Privacy
-------

By using our service, you consent to the terms of our privacy policy and agree that we may collect non-personal information as outlined below. If you have any questions or concerns about our privacy policy, please contact us.

### Website of Open-Meteo.com

The Open-Meteo.com website does not collect any data from our users, including personal information, usage statistics, or any other data that could be used to identify you. We do not use any cookies or tracking technologies, and we do not share any data with third-party providers.

We do not engage in any advertising or marketing practices that would require us to collect or use any personal information. You can use our website without any concern that your information will be shared with advertisers or marketing agencies.

### Blog and Newsletter

When you sign up for our newsletter, we collect your email address. We use a secure third-party email marketing platform [Substack.com](https://substack.com/privacy "Substack privacy policy") to manage our newsletter. This platform collects information such as your email address and IP address. We use this information solely for the purpose of sending you our newsletter and will not share or sell it with any third-party providers.

### Free Non-Commercial API Service

We may collect non-personal information, such as IP addresses, for technical reasons such as server maintenance or prevent misuse, but this information is not linked to user identities in any way.

For troubleshooting purposes, we keep webserver log files that may contain sensitive information such as geographical coordinates. We do not share this data with any third party. All log files will be deleted after a period of 90 days.

### Subscription to Paid API Services

When you sign up for our paid API service and make payments through Stripe, we may collect the following information:

* Contact information, such as your name, email address, and phone number
* Billing information, including your credit card details, billing address, and payment history
* Usage data and analytics, which may include information about how you interact with our service
* We may share your personal with Stripe, who assist us in processing payments and delivering our service. Stripe is obligated to protect your information and are prohibited from using it for any other purpose.
* You information is solely used process and manage your payments through Stripe, provide our API service, including customer support and troubleshooting

When using the API service, we gather certain information, including IP addresses and URLs, to monitor the usage of the API. This usage data is associated with your subscription. However, after a period of 90 days, all individual log files will be removed, and only aggregated usage data will be retained, such as the number of API calls per day.

We take appropriate measures to protect your personal information from unauthorized access, alteration, disclosure, or destruction. We maintain industry-standard security practices and regularly review and update our security measures to ensure the confidentiality and integrity of your information.

We will retain your personal information for as long as necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this privacy notice, unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by law.

You have the right to access, update, or delete your personal information. If you wish to exercise any of these rights or have any questions or concerns about our privacy practices, please contact us using the information provided below.

We may update this privacy notice from time to time. The updated version will be posted on our website, and a detailed change history is available on [GitHub](https://github.com/open-meteo/open-meteo-website/commits/main/src/routes/en/terms/%2Bpage.svelte "Modification history of terms of service").

Open-Meteo is operated by
-------------------------

OpenMeteo Zippenfenig  
c/o Patrick Zippenfenig  
Hintere Schilligmatte 6  
6463 Bürglen (UR)  
Switzerland

VAT CHE 327.264.349 MWST

Contact: [info@open-meteo.com](mailto:info@open-meteo.com)

Open-Meteo

Weather APIs

Other APIs

External

© 2022-2024 Copyright: Open-Meteo.com
